

# **Muhammad Tayyab U Rehman**

Phone number: (+92) 3092867068 (Mobile) | Email address: info.tayyab.cheema@gmail.com |

Address: Village and Post Office Dhola Kalan, Tehsil Phalia district Mandibahauddin, Pakistan (Home)

## ABOUT ME

I am a dedicated Computer Science graduate with strong skills in software development and a passion for new technologies. I have experience as a Full Stack developer, building scalable solutions, AI-powered applications, and SaaS platforms using cloud technologies. During my studies, I participated in various university societies and activities, which helped me develop teamwork and problem-solving skills. I also attended seminars to expand my knowledge and stay up-to-date with industry trends. I have completed additional courses to improve my abilities and am now excited to continue my education through a master's program to deepen my knowledge and contribute to advancements in computer science.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

30/10/2024 - CURRENT Jhelum, Pakistan

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER REV9 SOLUTIONS**

- · Leading the development of various projects.
- Integrating third-party services using webhooks and APIs.
- Developing Al-powered web applications for diverse solutions.
- Managing project timelines, resources and team coordination to ensure successful delivery.

15/04/2024 - 15/07/2024 Gujrat, Pakistan

### **BACKEND DEVELOPER SKILLSHAKS**

- Developed backend solutions, including REST APIs and payment integration.
- Contributed to building a subscription-based system.
- Worked with AWS S3 services and non-relational databases.
- Collaborated with frontend developers for smooth integration.
- Focused on securing the application by addressing vulnerabilities and improving safety

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

02/11/2020 - 02/08/2024 Guirat, Pakistan

## BS COMPUTER SCIENCE University Of Gujrat

The major modules I studied during this degree are:

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Advance Web System & Technology
- Artificial Intelligence
- Software Engineering
- Parallel and Distributed Computing
- Information Security and Computer Networks

Final grade 3.16 / 4.0

21/08/2017 - 04/09/2019 Phalia, Pakistan

## INTERMEDIATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Punjab College for Boys Phalia Campus

The major modules I studied during this course are:

- Physics
- Computer Science
- Mathematics

## MATRICULATION Ghazali Model High School Phalia

The major modules I studied during this course are:

- Physics
- Chemistry
- Mathematics
- Computer Science

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **URDU** 

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

## **COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

#### Soft Skills

- Adaptability
- · Problem-Solving
- Attention to Detail
- Time Management
- Effective Communication

## PROGRAMMING SKILLS

### Languages

- C++
- Java
- C#
- Python
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

## **Projects**

- Car Showroom Management System (C++ using Data Structures)
- Network Design and Implementation System (Cisco Packet Tracer)
- Pharmacy Management System (C#, MySql)
- Cars Price Predication System (Python, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, Flask, MySQL)
- Al-Driven Social Behavior Analysis (Python, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, NLP, Flask, MongoDB)
- Smart Cloud Storage Management (Javascript, AWS, Nodejs, MongoDB, Reactjs)
- Lifeflow One Stop Blood Donation Management System (React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongodb, TailwindCSS, Material UI)
- Smart List Zero (React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongodb, Material UI, Stripe API, Webhooks, Socket.io)
- Casemaster (Nestis, Postgresql, Paypal API)